We'll speak a little bit about removal from
office of directors, because it's a strict provision
of the CARMA 2020.
If a director is to be removed from
office, whether it's executive or non-executive, there's
a requirement that he or she is given
28 days notice of the intention to remove
them.
Within these 28 days, they have a right
to respond to the allegations made against them
or the reasons for which they're going to
be removed.
If it's a public company, the reasons have
to be published alongside the notice and the
response of the director to such allegations or
reasons would also be published as well.
And so to that extent, a lot of
companies would prefer that the director to be
removed is actually given the opportunity to resign.
And more so now that the requirement that
once the director is removed from office, he
or she can no longer hold the office
of a director, has caused many companies to
rethink the issue of removal.
It's a very extreme decision and extreme position
and so it's better to go the route
of having the director resign their role as
a director.
The board could potentially feel a casual vacancy
created by the exit of a director.
However, that casual vacancy has to be approved
by shareholders in the general meeting.